leadtools.com 2019-12-24

# Privacy Policy | LEAD Technologies, Inc.

LEAD Technologies, Inc. ("LEAD") has established the following privacy guidelines for the benefit of our customers and website visitors. 

## Categories of Information Collected and Stored.

**Personal Information.** Through your interaction with and use of the LEAD website or use of our software and services, we may collect certain personal identifying Information ("Personal Information"), which is information that identifies an individual or relates to an identifiable individual. Personal Information may include a person's name, physical address, telephone number, e-mail address, company affiliation and purchase history. LEAD requires that in some circumstances a prospect or customer provide Personal Information, for example, when you download a trial version of our software, purchase software, register software, sign up for newsletters or use our support site. 

**Non-Personal Information.** In general, you can visit the LEAD websites on the Internet without telling LEAD who you are or revealing any information about yourself. Our websites may collect and store anonymous information about your visits. This information includes the time and length of your visit, the pages you look at on our sites, and the site you visited just before coming to ours. We may also record the name of your Internet service provider, browser type, and country of origin. We use this information to monitor and measure traffic and to develop ideas for enhancing our sites. We also collect anonymous information both directly and via use of third party services such as Google Analytics and Click Dimensions regarding site traffic and click-thru. 

## Cookies and Tracking Technology.

LEAD uses cookies or similar technologies to improve your experience on our site, analyze trends, administer the website, track users' movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our website or service. 

Cookies allow a site to know if your computer has visited that site before. Cookies can then be used to help understand how the site is being used, help you navigate between pages efficiently, help remember your preferences, and generally improve your browsing experience. Cookies, by themselves, do not tell us your email address or other personal information. It is unique to your computer and can only be read by the server that gave it to you. 

## How We Use Information.

LEAD uses information for several general purposes: to fulfill your requests for certain products and services, to personalize your experience on our sites, to keep you up to date on the latest product announcements, software updates, special offers or other information we think you'd like to hear about, and to better understand your needs and provide you with better services. Should you download trial software, we may contact you for a limited period to communicate with you on the progress of your trial or to provide you with product education material. We may send you Newsletters, Code Tips and other informative emails. We may also use your information to send you direct marketing information or contact you for market research. We will not use or disclose your Personal Information to third parties except as expressly described in this Privacy Policy. 

##    Communication Opt-in. 

LEAD does not ask for Personal Information if you are simply browsing our website. LEAD does require that you provide your name, email address and other Personal Information when you are interfacing with LEAD in certain situations, including when you are downloading a trial version of our software, requesting pricing or licensing information, registering for technical support, registering for a give-a-way or other tradeshow or conference promotion, and purchasing a product or service. **By voluntarily providing your name and email address to LEAD when requested, you are explicitly "Opting-in" to receive product and services information, special offers, and general marketing material.** If you don't want LEAD to send you e-mail regarding LEAD products, services, or special offers, you may opt-out at any time. Opt-out links to unsubscribe to further marketing email communications are available on all marketing related e-mail communications. If you wish to do this, simply follow the instructions at the end of any email or go to the email subscription management page. Opting out of marketing related email communications does not preclude LEAD from sending you certain email communications such as communications related to product downloads, sales transactions, licensing compliance, account collection, software updates, software patches or fixes or responses to support issues. 

## Data and Submissions.

In the course of using certain of our software and support services, you may provide us with access to your data (including image files and personal information). If you choose to use our support services, you may post information on our support forums or submit information at your discretion in order to more fully describe a problem. Such information may include files containing data or programs. We agree that we will only use such information for providing technical support, bug fixes or developing enhancements and improvements to our software. 

## Information Transfer, Processing and Storage.

We may transfer, process and store data about you on servers located in a number of countries. Your Personal Information may therefore be transferred to, processed and stored in a country different from your country of residence, and be subject to privacy laws that are different from those in your country of residence. Specifically, Personal Information, as described in this policy, is stored on US-based data servers or in Cloud Storage Services managed by US companies. Information collected within the European Economic Area ("EEA") and Switzerland may, for example, be transferred to and processed by third parties referred to below that are located in a country outside of the EEA and Switzerland, where you may have fewer rights in relation to your Personal Information. By providing your Personal Information to us, you are consenting to the transfer, processing and storage of your Personal Information in countries outside of your country of residence and, specifically, the transfer, processing and storage of your Personal Information in the US. 

## Information Sharing and Disclosure.

Your Personal Information is never shared outside LEAD without your permission, except under conditions explained below. Inside LEAD, data is stored in controlled servers with limited access. Your information may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country where LEAD, its subsidiaries, affiliates or agents are located. 

LEAD may send your Personal Information to other companies or people under any of the following circumstances: (i) we need to share your information to provide the product or service you have requested or process a payment; (ii) we need to send the information to LEAD's authorized distributors who work on behalf of LEAD to provide a product or service to you (we will only provide those companies the information they need to contact you for purposes of delivering our products and services, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose). 

In certain situations, LEAD may be required to disclose Personal Information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We will also disclose your Personal Information if required to do so by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to enforce our Terms of Use, or in urgent circumstances, to protect personal safety, the public or our websites, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request. If LEAD is involved in a merger, acquisition, sale of all or a portion of its assets, or bankruptcy proceeding, you agree that the surviving entity/transferee will have the same rights and obligations as LEAD has with respect Personal Information hereunder. 

## Service Providers.

As described above, we may provide your Personal Information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as shipping your order, offering customer service, providing localized sales and support in a country other than the US. These companies are authorized to use Personal Information only as necessary to provide these services. If you make a purchase on our e-commerce site, we use third parties for credit card processing and ACH transactions and do not collect or store any credit card or bank account information in connection with purchases from our website. These third party providers have their own separate privacy policies and data collection policies, and LEAD has no responsibility or liability for such third party policies. More information regarding the third party policies is available, where applicable, on LEAD's on-line store. 

## Retention and Deletion.

LEAD will retain your Personal Information for as long as your account is active; as needed to provide you products or services; as needed for the purposes outlined in this policy; as necessary to comply with our legal obligations (e.g., to honor opt-outs), resolve disputes, enforce our agreements; or to the extent permitted by law. If requested, LEAD will delete your Personal Information in a manner designed to ensure that it cannot be reconstructed or read or will modify it in accordance with your written instructions. 

## Changes to Privacy Policy.

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time by posting a revised Privacy Policy on our website and changing the last modified date at the top of the Privacy Policy. If we make significant changes to the Privacy Policy, we will note the Privacy Policy has changed on the main page of the website and/or contact you by email. We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. 

Each email sent from LEAD contains an easy, automated way for you to cease receiving email from us, or to change your expressed interests. If you wish to do this, simply follow the instructions at the end of any email or go to the email subscription management page. 

## Social Media and Other Public Spaces.

LEAD's websites may link to third party social media sites such as Facebook and Twitter. Your interaction with these and other third party hosted social media sites is governed by the privacy and use policies of the entity hosting the third party site(s). Any information, including Personal Information, your user profile, and any content that you may post to a public space or website, such as a blog, forum or user group, will be available to other users of the public spaces and websites. 

## Contacting Us.

Please feel free to contact LEAD with any questions, comments, or concerns at: 

LEAD Technologies, Inc.   
Attn: Privacy Manager  
1927 South Tryon Street,  
Suite 200,  
Charlotte, NC 28203  
Email: [abuse@leadtools.com](mailto:abuse@leadtools.com)

When writing to us, please be sure to include your exact name, mailing address, telephone number and your specific question, comment or concern.
